Miloš Vasić, Software engineer

Date of birth: 25.07.1985.

E-Mail: i@mvasic.ru

Mobile:

+381 69 25 35 718 (Serbia) +7 966 323 77 17 (Russian Federation)

Locations:

Belgrade, Serbia Moscow (and Dubna), Russian Federation

Code:

GitFlic: https://gitflic.ru/user/milosvasic GitHub: https://github.com/milos85vasic

Networks:

Telegram: +381 69 25 35 718

Milos Vasic Telegram – Official: https://t.me/milosvasic

HelixTrack Telegram: https://t.me/helixtrack

HelixTrack Development Telegram: https://t.me/helixtrackdev

VK: https://vk.com/milos.vasic

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/милош-васић-53778682/

TenChat: https://tenchat.ru/milosvasic

Xing: https://www.xing.com/profile/Milos Vasic4/cv

Website: https://www.milosvasic.ru

Profile

Highly-skilled software engineer bringing years in software design, development, and integration. Advanced knowledge of Android, Java, Kotlin and C++. Experienced in the full project life cycle from design to implementation to integration. Author of programming books and open-source enthusiast.

Education

- Bachelor of Science: Informatics and Computing, 2008. University Singidunum, Belgrade (Serbia)
- M.Sc: Contemporary Information Technologies, 2014. University Singidunum, Belgrade (Serbia)

Main technology stack

Android, Kotlin, Java, Sqlite, Postgres, Gradle, Maven, C++, Cmake, React Native, TypeScript, JavaScript, Flutter, Dart, Swift, iOS, Dokcer, Kubernetes, Git, GitHub, GitFlic.

3rd party components:

Retrofit, OkHttp, Hawk, Firebase, etc.

Work history

Red Elf

Location:

Belgrade, Serbia

Company website:

https://www.red-elf.com https://github.com/red-elf

Time period:

- current working position, since 04/2020

Positions:

Owner, Software engineer, Project manager

Responsibilities:

Managing the development and actively contributing to development cycles for company clients and company projects:

- https://github.com/Helix-Track
- https://github.com/Server-Factory

Technologies:

Android, iOS, React Native, Kotlin, Java, Swift, C++, CMake, QT, TypeScript, JavaScript.

Team:

Work with my mobile development team for various clients:

- 1 Android senior
- 1 iOS senior
- 1 Android medior
- 1 QA senior
- 1 QA medior

Achievements:

- Complete development of the whole secure messaging solution SIP +

tunneling.

- Development of the mobile email client based on the raw SMTP + IMAP. Various heavy optimizations to support customers with the tens of thousands of messages. IMAP messages paginated fetching support.

Non-mobile development (open-source projects):

- Helix-Track, implementation the SQL to code utility – generates the source code models based on the SQL definition. The system architecture (the data layer, scaling, infrastructure, etc.)

https://www.helixtrack.ru https://github.com/Helix-Track

- Mail Server Factory (Server Factory project), the "code to infrastructure" solution:

https://mailserverfactory.ru https://github.com/Server-Factory/Mail-Server-Factory https://github.com/Server-Factory

Mobile development:

Gelato

Location:

Fully remote client

Complete maintenance and work on the new implementations on the existing project based on the React Native technology. Binding the native Android and iOS libraries for the final use use under the React Native codebase.

Client's website:

https://www.optimalprint.com/

Time period:

- from 07/2022 until 07/2023,

Positions:

Mobile software engineering, React Native

Responsibilities:

Managing the development and actively contributing the development on the React Native framework based product.

Technologies:

Android, iOS, React Native, TypeScript, JavaScript, Kotlin, Java, Swift.

TN-TECH

Location:

Novi Sad, Serbia (part-time, fully remote)

Company website:

http://www.tn-tech.co.rs/

Time period:

- current working position, since 03/2017

Position:

Head of research and mobile development

Responsibilities:

Overseeing all mobile development as well as leading the company's research division to improve and optimize cross-platform development and integration with AI and ML tools and libraries.

Technology:

Java, Kotlin, QT, QML, C++, Python

Team:

- 1 Android senior
- 1 iOS senior
- 1 QA senior
- 1 C++ senior

Achievements:

- Active development of the native Android and the cross-platform QT framework software
- Management of the mobile and QA teams

Projects:

- SekurMessenger, software for enterprise secure messaging and conferencing
- SekurSuite, secure and private document storage and sharing in Switzerland
- SekurMail, secure mail client for the Sekur network users

http://www.sekur.ch

- Muwasalati, It is a Code of Conduct mobile App, owned and monitored by the Land Transport Regulatory Commission LTRC. It aims to collect data from the App users on violation of conduct on the public transport and its facilities that could be caused by passengers, operators, and employees of the public transport, aiming at improving the quality of the public transport services in Jordan.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.muwasalati.jo

- BusRide platform: Design, implementation, and maintenance of apps for parents and bus drivers for BusRide collaboration platform between parents, school bus drivers, and school management. Both applications (parent and driver's apps) are developed in Kotlin with Android SDK.

Harness.io

Location:

Belgrade, Serbia

Company website:

http://harness.io/

Time period:

- from 05/2021 until 07/2022

Position:

Staff software engineer

Responsibilities:

Managing and overseeing the SDKs development on the Feature Flags project.

Technologies:

Technologies for 12 different SDKs. Some of them are: Java, Kotlin, Swift, C#, Ruby, etc.

Team:

- 1 mobile android senior
- 3 GoLang seniors
- 1 .net senior
- 3 Java seniors
- 3 JavaScript / TypeScript seniors
- 3-5 medior developers for additional development / maintenance work
- 1 outsources team for the .net development

Achievements:

- Active development work on the Harness "Feature Flags" mobile SDKs (Android, iOS, Flutter, React Native)
- Binding (wrapping) Android and iOS SDK codebase for use in Flutter and React Native SDKs
- Active development work on the Harness "Feature Flags" Java SDK
- Harness "Feature Flags" Ruby SDK
- Active development work on the Harness "Feature Flags" .net SDK
- Active development work on the core Harness platform (integration of the Feature Flag SDK into the platform)

Enreach

Location:

Belgrade, Serbia

Company website:

http://enreach.com/

Time period:

- from 02/2020 until 05/2021

Position:

Lead software engineer for Android platform.

Responsibilities:

Influencing and overseeing Android development on main company projects:

- Coligo Mobile, software for enterprise secured messaging and conferencing:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=io.summa.coligo.softphone

- UMC, Unified Mobile Client (currently under development)

Technologies:

Java, Kotlin, C++

Team:

- 2 Android seniors
- 2 Android mediors
- 2 iOS seniors
- 1 iOS junior
- 3 QA seniors

Achievements:

- Work on several messaging solutions with following challenges: websockets communication, real-time responsive UI, managing the call states, whole database stack (Sqlite), parallel background processing (event driven), Binding the C++ libraries for use in Android (JNI) and iOS.

Leica Geosystems

Location:

Heerbrugg, Switzerland

Company website:

https://leica-geosystems.com/

Time period:

from 05/2019 until 02/2020

Position:

Senior software engineer for Android and iOS

Responsibilities:

Developing mobile software for Leica's signature 3D scanners. Optimizing and resolving complex software problems in order to achieve cutting edge performance.

Team:

- 5 Android seniors
- 3 iOS seniors
- 3 C++ seniors
- 3 medior developers for additional development support
- 3 QA seniors

Achievements:

- Development of the real-time responsive UI connected to the 3D scanner device's event bus
- Extending the existing C++ codebase and sharing it between the Android and iOS platform
- Work on the Android and iOS platforms both (development of features on both platforms side by side)
- Development of the communication layer for the interaction with 3D scanners

Technologies:

Java, Kotlin, C++, Swift, Python

Project:

- **Leica Cyclone Field 360**, as part of the Leica Geosystems Reality Capture Solution, the Leica Cyclone FIELD 360 app links the 3D data acquisition in the field with the RTC360 laser scanner or with the BLK360 imaging laser scanner and data registration with Leica Cyclone REGISTER 360 post-processing office software.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.leicageosystems.cyclone.field360

Robert Bosch

Location:

Belgrade, Serbia

Company website:

https://www.bosch.rs/

Time period:

from 04/2016 until 01/2018

Position:

Lead Android software engineer on SDK for Connected Vehicles project

Technologies:

Java, Kotlin, C++

Team:

- 2 Android seniors
- 2 Android mediors
- 2 Android juniors
- 3 iOS seniors
- 2 QA seniors
- 2 QA juniors
- 3-5 students

Achievements:

- The whole Android SDK development: core, communication layer, persistence layer
- Parallel processing of signals data from OBD2 and persisting to database layer (SQLite)
- Development of processing strategies that can be applied through the SDK configuration
- Bluetooth stack communication.

Project:

- Connected Vehicles SDK: Android SDK for the car industry used by very respectful clients. Connected Vehicles SDK is an Android library written in Java and Kotlin with the purpose of establishing connectivity between the car's OBD2 and mobile devices.

Deploy Inc.

Location:

Belgrade, Serbia

Company website:

https://www.deployinc.com/

Time period:

from 09/2014 until 04/2016

Position:

Senior software engineer & Team leader

Team:

- 5 Android seniors
- 5 Android mediors
- 3-5 Android juniors
- 5 QA seniors
- 3 QA mediors

Achievements:

- Development of the device and power management
- Infra red communication stack development (regular and IR relays)
- Integration of the support for various hardware (TVs, STBs, Spundbars, etc.) and providers (cable providers, such as Dish Hopper, Time Warner Cable, etc.)
- Work on the persistence layer (SQLite) and content providers implementation.

Technologies:

Java, Android, Android OS

Project:

- Ray Super Remote (now owned by Amazon): http://www.ray.co.

Responsibilities:

- Led a group of several engineers in designing and development of Android-based software solutions.
- One of the main developers on Device and Power Management for the device's core functionality.
- Worked on various enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks.
- Identified and suggested new technologies and tools for enhancing product value and increasing team productivity.

Youngculture

Location:

Belgrade, Serbia

Position:

Lead software engineer for Android platform

Time period:

from 03/2013 until 09/2014

Technologies:

Java, Android

Tehnicom Solutions

Location:

Belgrade, Serbia

Position:

Lead Web software engineer & Android software engineer

Time period:

from 10/2010 until 03/2013

Technologies:

PHP, CakePHP, Java, Android, C++

Author work

- Fundamental Kotlin: revised (September 6, 2022.)
- Fundamental Kotlin, Second Edition (2018.)
- Fundamental Kotlin (2016.)

http://www.fundamental-kotlin.com/

- Mastering Android Development with Kotlin (2017.) https://www.packtpub.com/application-development/mastering-android-development-kotlin
- Building Applications with Spring 5 and Kotlin (2018.) https://www.packtpub.com/application-development/building-applicationsspring-5-and-kotlin